+880 1961-896264 zaberhakim666@gmail.com personal-website/zaber

Zaber Ibn Abdul Hakim

scholar.google.com/zaber kaggle.com/zaber linkedin.com/in/zaber

I have gained extensive experience in deep learning over the past 4 years. Initially, I actively participated in multiple competitions on Kaggle, DrivenData, and the IEEE Signal Processing Society. Ranked as a **Kaggle Competition Master**, I attained the best overall Kaggle rank of 385 among 200,000+ users. Additionally, I have engaged in various research activities and authored multiple research publications. Currently, I am working as a machine learning engineer.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

March 2018 — May 2023

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
CGPA: 3.83 (out of 4.00) | Enlisted for Deans List Award

EXPERIENCE

■ Machine Learning Engineer

Jun 2023 - Current

IQVIA

- Developing a general and multi-purpose fine-tuned Large Language Model
- Developing intelligent agents to answer clients' natural language queries
- Developing FastAPI & FlaskAPI for the ML algorithms to communicate with the backend
- Onboarding duties of recently joined employees

■ Research Intern Jan 2022 — Dec 2023

Xu Lab

Carnegie Mellon University

- Improved the understanding of different sentence components in multiple video-language joint learning tasks.
- Devised a solution to detect anomalous events in automated tools during experiments in a laboratory using recorded videos.
- completed the writing of two scientific manuscripts. One accepted and another under review.
- Supervised one undergraduate student in a research work

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

■ "Leveraging Generative Language Models for Weakly Supervised Sentence Component Analysis in Video-Language Joint Learning",

ZIA Hakim*, NH Sarker*, RP Singh, B Paul, A Dabouei, M Xu

Under Review in 2024 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2024 (CVPR 2024)

Paper Link

■ "ArtiFact: A Large-Scale Dataset with Artificial and Factual Images for Generalizable and Robust Synthetic Image Detection",

MA Rahman*, B Paul*, NH Sarker*, ZIA Hakim*, SA Fattah

Published in 2023 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP 2023)

Paper Link Dataset

 $\blacksquare \ "Detecting Anomalies from \ Liquid \ Transfer \ Videos \ in \ Automated \ Laboratory \ Setting",$

NH Sarker, **ZIA Hakim**, A Dabouei, MR Uddin, Z Freyberg, A MacWilliams, J Kangas, M Xu

Published in Frontiers in Molecular Biosciences (under AI in Biological and Biomedical Imaging)

Paper Link

■ "Attention-Driven Multi-Modal Fusion: Enhancing Sign Language Recognition and Translation",

ZIA Hakim, RM Swargo, MA Adnan

Arxiv Preprint

Paper Link

+880 1961-896264 zaberhakim666@gmail.com personal-website/zaber

Zaber Ibn Abdul Hakim

scholar.google.com/zaber kaggle.com/zaber linkedin.com/in/zaber

MACHINE LEARNING COMPETITIONS

■ SIIM-FISABIO-RSNA COVID-19 Detection

Aug 2021

Identify and localize COVID-19 abnormalities on chest radiograph images

4th Place out of 1305 teams. (**Gold Medal Winner at Kaggle**) | Best Student Team Award Winner

■ HP Presents Kaggle Days World Championship 2022

Sept 2022

Winner of Shanghai Regional

Selected as one of the top 36 data science teams globally to participate in the final event at Barcelona, Spain

■ Deep Chimpact

Nov 2021

Depth Estimation of animals from Images for Wildlife Conservation

Winner | 1^{st} *Place out of 313 teams*

■ IEEE Signal Processing Cup

May 2022

Differentiation between original human speech and synthetic speech.

Winner | Presented our solution at ICASSP 2022, Singapore

■ IEEE Video & Image Processing Cup

Sept 2022

Synthetic Image Detection.

First Runner-up

■ NFL 1st and Future - Impact Detection

Jan 2021

Detection of helmet impacts between players in videos of NFL games.

 25^{th} Place out of 460 teams. (Silver Medal Winner at Kaggle)

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

■ How Are You

■ Organizer

A Mental Health Screening Site

Used Flask, ReactJS and PostgreSQL

■ BUET Alumni Portal

An Portal For Alumni for my university

Used Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PostgreSQL

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

■ Technical Committee Chair

May 2022 - May 2023

IEEE Computer Society

"Bangladesh Univerisity Of Engineering & Technology (BUET)" Student Branch Chapter

DL Sprint - BUET CSE Fest 2022

Jul 2022

First Inter-University Deep Learning Competition hosted by BUET

This competition won **Kaggle Community Competition Creator Prize: July Month** for its problem statement, community involvement, and impact

■ Speaker: Introduction to Kaggle and Deep Learning

Jun 2022

An introductory workshop organized by "IEEE Computer Society BUET Student Branch" 150+ students from different universities attended this session